okay let's discuss the solution for our
flushy stols and forwarding quiz we have
this five-stage pipeline we said already
that for control dependencies we have to
use flushes we have fetched the wrong
instructions delaying them or trying to
fix the values they read is not going to
help us so here we have to flush and we
don't stall or forward for this data
dependence at the time when the load is
reading the R1 here the multi L is
producing the result here the multiply
has the result at the end of that cycle
and the load will need to compute the
address at the beginning of the next
cycle so here we can forward the value
of R1 from the multiply to load and
don't have to stall again we don't want
to use flushes here the final question
is whether the loads result of R1 which
needs to be fed to the here can be
forwarded or do we have to stall when
the ad is reading R1 here the load is
here Computing the address it still has
not accessed memory in the next cycle
the ad is Computing using the wrong
value of R1 while the load is still
loading memory so the load only at the
end of this cycle has the proper value
of R1 whereas the ad at the end of that
cycle has already computed the wrong
result so in this case we have to stall
interestingly enough we will actually
after that one stall cycle forward to
avoid stalling more so we here we have
to have a stall and we can after the
stall do forwarding or just stall more
but this is one of those situations
where forwarding cannot help you you
have to stall for a data dependence